registerbynet.com 2010-01-14

# Melville Data Services :: Privacy Policy

This site is operated by Melville Exhibition and Events Services Limited. This privacy policy applies to the practices of Melville with respect to the information held about you by Melville and to the information which Melville collects about you online at its web site, [http://www.melville.co.uk](http://www.melville.co.uk/).

Please note that although Melville’s web site is located in the United Kingdom, Melville may collect, store and process your personal information in the United States or in other countries outside of the country in which you live. The United States and/or these countries may not offer a level of privacy protection for your personal information as great as is offered in the country in which you live.

**Information Held and/or Collected**  
Melville collects your information (‘Personal Information’) if you visit the Melville web site and wish to register, purchase products, obtain information regarding our products or services, request other information or otherwise communicate with us. Melville may also hold your Personal Information having received it from a third party or from you by means other than the website. For example, where your Personal Information is passed to us by an event organizer in order that we may offer our products and services in connection with that event to you. ‘Personal Information’ means any information relating to a natural person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, from that information. The Personal Information we hold and / or collect about you can include your name, business address, telephone number, e-mail address, what web sites visitors to the Melville web site come from, which pages are visited at the Melville web site, and information about online activities that are directly linked to them. New Personal Information may be merged with other Personal Information Melville already holds.

**Use of Personal Information**  
Melville will collect and use your Personal Information to render services to you, respond to your enquiries, and to market and sell to you products and services offered by Melville or its associated companies. In addition, Melville may use Personal Information to conduct other legitimate business activities, such as protecting the security of the Melville web site and of Melville's networks, preventing fraud, complying with law and complying with a legally permitted inquiry by a government agency or regulator.

If necessary for these purposes, Melville may transfer your Personal Information to third parties and these third parties may use your Personal Information for such purposes. These third parties may include Melville's associated companies, advisors, companies providing products and services to Melville and, to the extent required by law, regulatory authorities.

Melville may also transfer your Personal Information to companies that have entered into a contract with Melville to offer or endorse Melville’s products or services.

If you purchase products or services online via the Melville web site, your Personal Information will be used to complete any transactions you wish to enter into, including credit card processing and credit checks.

If all or any part of the Melville business is sold to a third party, we may transfer Personal Information to the third party buyer as part of the assets of the business.

**Your Control and “Opt Out” Choices**  
You may request, at any time, that the Personal Information you provide to Melville via the Melville web site is not used for direct marketing purposes by Melville or transferred by Melville to third parties for marketing purposes by clicking on the “opt out” link at the foot of this privacy policy.

In addition, certain e-mails sent to you from Melville will contain an “opt out” or unsubscribe link. You may “opt out” of receiving the certain e-mails by clicking on the “opt out” link at the foot of this privacy policy or by clicking on the “opt out” link provided in the e-mail that may be sent to you.

You should address any questions about, or requests concerning the handling of your Personal Information by e-mail to: [privacy@Melville.co.uk](mailto:privacy@Melville.co.uk). Reasonable steps will be taken to verify your identity before making corrections to your Personal Information. If you do not wish to receive information from Melville or be contacted by email and / or if you wish Melville to delete from its records all your Personal Information, you should also contact Melville by e-mail at [privacy@Melville.co.uk](mailto:privacy@Melville.co.uk). Whilst Melville will delete your Personal Information from its active database, it will retain such records (which may include some or all of your Personal Information) for such period as may reasonably be required in connection with any transactions affected by you.

**Melville’s data security**  
To prevent unauthorized access to your Personal Information, we have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. We will use various electronic means to keep transaction information transferred over the Web as secure as generally available transaction technology reasonably permits.

**Use of ‘cookies’**  
When you visit the Melville web site and enter your details on to the site, we will place a ‘cookie’ on your computer, which helps us identify you more quickly when you return. Cookies are small pieces of information stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive and are used in website system administration to keep track of movement of an individual from one screen to another. We will use cookies alone or in conjunction with other devices, to understand how you arrived at our web site, to identify your computer when using our website in the future and to identify you for future marketing. This information may also be used by our staff to detect and resolve web site problems.

It is usually possible for you to change your browser settings should you wish to prevent acceptance of a cookie.

**Links**  
To offer you products and servies in which you might be interested, we provide links to third party web sites. When you click on a link, you will be transferred out of the Melville web site. Melville does not control these linked web sites and you should consult that site's privacy policy before providing any Personal Information.

**Changes in practices**  
This Privacy Policy may change from time to time and any changes will be posted here. If we materially change our privacy practices as to how we use or share your Personal Information with third parties, we will take reasonable measures to inform you of these changes in advance. You will then have a reasonable opportunity to change your opt-out preference.

**Opt Out Link**  
Your Personal Information is held by us in accordance with the terms of our Privacy Policy. Your details may have been provided to us by a show organiser in connection with your show registration. Your details may be used to keep you informed about our future products, services and events. If you do not wish to receive such information from us by e-mail or would like to place a complaint regarding current electronic communications, please e-mail [privacy@melville.co.uk](mailto:privacy@melville.co.uk) above.

Company Name: Melville Exhibition and Events Services Limited

Registered Office: Unit 1, Perimeter Road, National Exhibition Centre, Birmingham, B40 1PJ

Registration Number: 2930892

OPT OUT LINK: [privacy@melville.co.uk](mailto:privacy@melville.co.uk)
